

# Mehmet Akif Tütüncü

Senior Software Engineer

- Amsterdam, Netherlands

♠ https://akif.dev

nakiftutuncu

**in** makiftutuncu

**y** makiftutuncu

I'm mainly focused on backend. I have more than 9 years of professional experience in software industry. I've worked with companies around the world and conducted consulting/training. I have extensive JVM knowledge and proficiency in Scala, Java, Kotlin using both object-oriented and functional programming. I have skills in CI/CD, testing, databases, cloud applications, micro-services. I am a fan of open-source software.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Senior Software Engineer @ iO

(Dec 2022 - Present)

Before joining a client project as a consultant, I acted as a developer advocate. I co-organized a workshop, wrote on company blog, attended recruitment interviews/reviews and worked on improving the hiring process.

https://iodigital.com

# Senior Software Engineer @ Scalac

(Nov 2021 - Oct 2022)

I worked with Conduktor as a consultant. I migrated part of their legacy Java API to a new Scala service. It included an automated mechanism to check for correctness. Then I worked on admin features of Conduktor Platform, spanning multiple Conduktor products.

https://scalac.io

# Software Engineer @ Numbrs

(Nov 2020 - Oct 2021)

I worked in Personal Finance Management team. I was responsible for developing new features to Numbrs app backend.

https://www.numbrs.com

# Senior Software Engineer @ sahibinden.com

(Aug 2019 - Nov 2020)

I worked in the search team. I usually dealt with search, promotions and categories domains. I also took the lead on automating the process of updating location and geo data.

https://sahibinden.com

#### Software Engineer @ VNGRS

(May 2017 - Aug 2019)

I consulted in multiple projects. In MAF Properties team, I worked in the kick-off process for their latest product. In Beam team, I helped migrate and maintain a mobile payment system. In Socrata team, I helped design, develop and maintain multiple backend projects.

https://vngrs.com

#### Software Engineer @ Linovi

(Oct 2013 - Oct 2016)

I started as part-time here. Then I joined Shazam team full-time. I had varying tasks from developing features, fixing bugs, writing automated tests to maintaining projects.

### Android Developer @ iDivino

(Aug 2012 - Aug 2013)

I worked part-time on developing games for preschool children.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Izmir Institute of Technology

(Aug 2009 - Jun 2014)

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Engineering

Education in English, focused on software, started my career halfway through with internships and part-time positions

#### **SKILLS**

#### Frameworks/Libraries/Tools

Akka, AWS, cats, circe, Docker, Elasticsearch, git, Gradle, http4s, JUnit, Kafka, Play Framework, Quill, SBT, ScalaTest, Spring Framework, tapir, ZIO

#### **Databases**

Cassandra, DynamoDB, Firebase, MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Redis

# **Progamming Languages**

Go, Java, Kotlin, Scala

# **Techniques**

Agile, CI/CD, DDD, Kanban, Microservices, SCRUM, TDD

#### PERSONAL PROJECTS

# **Effect**

Functional effect library in Scala https://github.com/makiftutuncu/effect Scala, Functional Effect, Error Handling

#### Muezzin

Android application and server https://github.com/makiftutuncu/Muezzin

Scala, Java, Play Framework, PostgreSQL, Anorm, Akka

#### **Bookstore**

A project demonstrating automated testing on backend https://github.com/makiftutuncu/bookstore

Scala, Finch, ScalaTest, Postman, Docker, Flyway, Doobie, PostgreSQL

#### k-retry

Naive retry implementation

https://github.com/makiftutuncu/k-retry

Kotlin, JUnit

# TALKS AND PRESENTATIONS

# Things I Learned Building a Functional Effect System

Functional Scala 2022

https://youtu.be/ZNB2epqQhc8

#### Dealing with Errors on JVM with e

ScalaUA 2020

https://youtu.be/HAQZtTZae\_Q

#### Kotlin for Backends

sahibinden.com D2D

https://github.com/makiftutuncu/kotlin-for-backends

#### Typeclass 101

VNGRS Lightning Talks

https://youtu.be/jPiM9uBHpWI

# Testing Web Backends With Scala

Test Hive

https://youtu.be/QnK8pyGUOac

# Working Remotely From Turkey

Interview with DevTech Community

https://youtu.be/VbvIIcR-JYg

## **LANGUAGES**

#### Turkish

Native

# English

Professional

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

#### Complete Guide to Elasticsearch

Udemy

#### (Jun 2020)

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate (May 2018)

Amazon

# **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

# Kodluyoruz

(Dec 2020 - Jan 2021)

# Izmir Institute of Technology

(Jan 2013 - Apr 2013)

Instructor

I gave introduction to Scala and functional programming I gave Android lectures in student club at my university.

lectures.

# Instructor